Guide to the Radio TV Services Records, circa 1937 - 2008
Duke University. University Archives
- Film and Video circa 1937-1987 and undated
  - Film, C and D series 1951-1974, undated
    - Campus Scenes: TV Use, circa 1955, 1 film, no reel, no core, in 7 inch can. (Reel C-147)
      Note on can: Shots of library and campus... Used on a TV show on WUNC-TV, Apr. 17, 1955.
    - Cutouts from This is Duke, undated, 1 film: sd., col.; on core, no reel, in 7-inch can. (Reel C-148)
    - This is Duke, undated, 1 film: sil., col.; on core, no reel, in 10-inch can. (Reel C-149)
    - This is Duke, undated, 1 film: sil., col.; on core, no reel, in 10-inch can. (Reel C-149)
    - Study-In in Allen Building, 1969, 1 film reel: b&w; 7 inch. (Reel C-150)
    - Nuclear Structure Lab: Moving Accelerator from RR Building, Feb. 5, 1968, 1 film reel: 3 inch, in 7-inch can. (Reel C-157)
    - Art Museum, undated, 2 film reels: 3 inch, in 7-inch can. (Reel C-158)
    - Duke Gardens, Apr. 22, 1970, 1 film reel: si., col.; 3 inch, in 7-inch can. (Reel C-159)
    - Presentation Ceremony of some type at Duke Homestead. Apr. 28, 1968, 1 film reel: si., b&w; 3 inch, in 7-inch can. (Reel C-160)
      Label on can: List of order of shots is enclosed. See Audio Tape #B-650 for sound of this event. [This list is in Box 14, Folder 12.]
    - U.S.S. Monitor Discovery, Mar. 7, 1974, 1 film reel: sd.; 7 inch. (Box 15, Reel C-163)
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-3
      Note on can: Orig. Magnetic Sound. Original film of news conference held to announce the finding of the U.S.S. Monitor by Duke Univ. and other researchers.
    - U.S.S. Monitor Discovery, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch, in 7 inch can. (Reel C-164-A, Reel 1 of 3)
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-4
      Note on reel: Alcoa Seaprobe on Sat. in later March, 1974, when it was to [sic] public inspection. Note on can: Color Original. See file cards for detailed contents of each reel. Each reel is labeled in abbreviated fashion.
    - U.S.S. Monitor Discovery, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch, in 7 inch can. (Reel C-164-A, Reel 2 of 3)
      Note on reel: Shots of Artifacts recovered from Monitor site by US Navy LCU. (Film made in port.) Film is edited. Note on can: Color Original. See file cards for detailed contents of each reel. Each reel is labeled in abbreviated fashion.
    - U.S.S. Monitor Discovery, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch, in 5 inch can. (Reel C-164-B, Reel 3 of 3)
      Note on reel: Film made from U.S. Navy videotape of Monitor on ocean floor. Poor quality. Edited. Note on can: Color Original. See file cards for detailed contents of this reel. The reel itself is labeled in abbreviated fashion.
    - Terry Sanford Inauguration, undated, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel D-2, Reel 1 of 2)
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-6
      Highlights of Terry Sanford's inauguration appear on Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-12
      Highlights of Terry Sanford's inauguration appear on Reference Copy: VHS. UA88-57-12
      Note on can: Descriptions of shots are enclosed. [Typed and hand-written shot list removed from can and placed in Folder 4, Box 15.]
    - Terry Sanford Inauguration, undated, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel D-2, Reel 2 of 2)
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-7
      Note enclosed in can: Entire reel is portions of Sanford's speech (see Reel 2 designation on handwritten list of shots in can with #D-2, Reel 1, for more detailed list of quotes which are on the film. [Typed and hand-written shot list removed from can and placed in Folder 4, Box 15.]
    - Terry Sanford's first news conference after being named President of Duke University, Dec. 14, 1969, 1 film reel: 5 inch, in 7 inch can. (Reel D-4)
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-5
      Highlights of Terry Sanford's first news conference appear on Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-12
      Highlights of Terry Sanford's first news conference appear on Reference Copy: VHS. UA88-57-12
    - Selected highlights of the Epoch Campaign announcement. Speakers included Sanford, Jones, McMahon, Sept. 27, 1973, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel D-8)
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-9
      Highlights of the Epoch Campaign Announcement appear on Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-12
      Highlights of the Epoch Campaign Announcement appear on Reference Copy: VHS. UA88-57-12
      There is a xeroxed script for the Epoch Campaign entitled For Humankind and History: A Time for Greatness at Duke in folder 5, box 3.
    - Card Tricks: Several years, '51, '52, and others, 1951-1952, undated, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Doing Good: A Roll Original, undated, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Doing Good: B Roll Original, undated, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Football: Duke -Tenn. Composite Sound Print, 1953, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Football: Duke -Tenn. Composite Sound Print #2, 1953, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Football: Duke - Tenn. HiLites Magnetic Sound, 1953, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel No number)
    - The Luxury of Doing Good, Apr. 17, 1974, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel No number)
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-8
    - Monitor: Ship returns to port, undated, 1 film reel: 3 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Reel C: Duke WWII footage, Rose Bowl Football, undated, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel No number)
    - "A Time for Greatness at Duke", undated, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel No number)
  - Film, Numbered series, circa 1937-1960, undated
    All film in this series is 16mm. The film is stored on a variety of different sized reels and in different sized cans.
    Some of the subjects depicted include football, basketball, the 1954 Orange Bowl, Joe College, campus scenes, Duke Gardens, the Duke Marine Laboratory, commencement, and homecoming.
    The film in this series is not indexed in the card file index in Box 3. However, a typewritten list titled Description of Films describes the contents of some of these films, and descriptions from the list have been included in this finding aid. The original list is in Folder 7, Box 16.
    The films in this series were originally numbered 1 through 46. That arrangement has been retained here. A number of unnumbered reels were received by the archives in the same boxes as these films and seem to belong in this series. Films without numbers are listed at the end of the series, arranged in alphabetical order by title.
    Since the majority of these films are numbered using a system other than the one used by Radio-TV Services, and since most of them appear to have been shot before the creation of the department, it is assumed that they were inherited from some other organization.
    - Orange Bowl Halftime, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch. (Box 16, Reel 5)
      From Description of Films:
      Float in the center of the football field. It's turning around.
      Bands in the middle of field-lots of activity out on field, floats leave field.
      Very dark. 200 ft. long.
    - Duke Band in Stadium, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch. (Reel 6)
      Looks like what is now Wallace Wade Stadium.
      Drum corps on field.
      Duke Band coming out on field/performs/at the end spells out D-U-K-E.
    - J. C. Parade at Gardens, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch. (Reel 7)
      A parade of Duke students (maybe Joe College).
      Gardens/people sitting.
    - Untitled, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch. (Reel 8)
      Two The Ends.
      Alumni House.
      Someone walking across campus.
    - Campus Scenes, undated, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel 9)
      black and white (badly scratched).
      Chapel (top to bottom).
      Union Bldg.
      Library side pan to right.
      Davison Bldg. (don't see it).
      Clock Tower.
      Med School.
      Wannamaker Dorm.
    - Basketball, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch. (Reel 11)
      Duke team #'s 10 and 31.
      Playing a team wearing white uniforms with red letters.
      Duke player (20).
      (10) is a forward (20) is a guard (33) maybe center.
    - Duke Marine Laboratory, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch. (Reel 12)
      Numerous tape splices.
      Color scenes taken down at the Duke Marine Laboratory.
      Feeding of birds.
    - Football Clips, undated, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel 13)
      Scene looking from top of Chapel down campus drive.
      Bill Murray talks to football player (60).
      Football practice in background.
      Photograph of Football squad.
      Photos of individual players: #'s 83, 71, 63.
      Players getting down over the ball center (58).
      #'s 60, 74, 80 all lined up being introduced & charge down the field.
      Orange Bowl Classic 1957 Miami, Florida.
      Duke vs. Nebraska.
      Parade down field for Orange Bowl.
      Football plays from that game.
      Crowd shot at end.
    - Football, undated, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel 14)
      Coach Bill Murray & players on field.
      Players numbers we can see: 18, 46, 33, 35.
      20-going to kick ball.
      18-pass the ball.
      37-fullback/halfback.
      46-carrying ball.
      35-carrying ball.
      41-carrying ball and passing.
      Entire squad running through a practice scrimmage play-48 receives.
      Parade down field.
      Football plays Duke vs. ? (some kind of bowl game) was a touchdown made.
      Duke vs. Nebraska in Orange Bowl. Score on board Duke 7 - Nebraska 0 (nearly 12 minutes to go when this picture was taken.
    - Orig. '55 Team [?] & Coaches for TV Clips, 1955, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel 15)
      Original Label-Duke University #1 Football Clips original 1955.
      (almost same as 13).
      Coach Bill Murray talking with player (60).
      Line-up of front line.
      83 stands up runs off to side.
      71 runs forward.
      63 lined up over ball.
      59
      60
      74
      80
      Centers the ball.
      Starts over this sequence.
      Looking down from top of chapel then do a diamond wipe to football field.
      Coach Bill Murray in huddle with players.
      20 kicks the ball.
      18 pass.
      37 runs.
      46 runs.
      35 runs.
      41 takes the ball and jump passes.
      Entire offensive line running a practice scrimmage.
      Color flag of the United States on field and it says Nebraska & Duke.
      Band on field playing.
    - Untitled, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch. (Reel 16)
      (full of tape splices)
      Group of men sitting around table, individual close-up of two men, then group shot of the men again.
      Overlooking (possibly) the hospital parking lot.
      Into the hospital.
      Two people in white coats working with a patient.
      Close-up of computer machine.
      Band performing on field.
      Card section at Duke Stadium-face of pirate.
      Brief crowd shot.
      Somebody lecturing (very dark).
      Some people (you tried to identify some Charles Wade and Clarence Whitefield).
      Arthur Larson talking on the phone.
      Looking through the gardens (long).
      Golf course and putting green.
      People at edge of swimming pool (out of focus).
      Air ROTC marching pass briefly.
      Rifle inspection.
    - Army-Duke Band, 1954, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel 17)
      Band on field, another band getting ready to go out on field.
      Duke going through formations.
    - Duke vs. Georgia Tech, circa 1953, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel 18)
      Football play in process.
      Beautiful run for gain.
      (38) Duke quarterback/other numbers 86, 28, 74 drive down about 15 yard line almost at the goal line.
      No score.
    - Duke vs. Tennessee (football), undated, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel 20)
      original footage (tape edits in it).
      Program of game.
      Looking down from top of chapel at the city.
      Panning across top of buildings.
    - Year at Duke leftover, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch. (Reel 22)
      (film very scratched).
      Subtitle-East Duke Bldg.
      Subtitle-West Duke Bldg.
      Giles Dorm.
      East Campus Library.
      Scenes of the 95th Commencement.
      Reception held on East Campus honoring graduating seniors.
      Picture of President Flowers walking.
      Following number of distinguished people.
      Procession people in academic gown.
    - Duke Band, 1953, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel 23)
    - Year at Duke leftover, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 5 inch. (Reel 24)
      (soft focus).
      Band goes through different formations on field.
    - Titles: Duke Army Game, undated, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel 25)
    - A Year at Duke, undated, 1 film reel: 3 inch. (Reel 26)
      Aerial view of Duke West Campus.
      Football field.
      One of the quads.
      East Campus.
      Aerial view of East Campus.
      Senior class raises flag to open academic year.
      Flag being presented to Hollis Edens.
      Flag being raised up pole.
      ****SOMEONE NEEDS TO SEE THIS MAN WHO COULD IDENTIFY HIM.
      Annual Homecoming-students erect homecoming decorations.
      Duke vs. Virginia.
      Decorations finish out reel.
    - Football Clips, 1955, 1 film reel: b&w; 7 inch. (Reel 28)
      Same as reel 13 and 15
    - untitled, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 7 inch. (Reel 29)
      From Description of Films: Ernie Greup talking to two men on sofa.
      Sign on wall behind men Here is your Hoof'n'Horn Show Laughing With You.
      Float people dressed in Scottish uniforms/some kind of parade.
      Piano and band being unloaded.
      Bunch of people in front of building on east.
      Girls in dressing room fixing hair.
      Band performing Les Brown and his Band of Renown graduate of Duke.
      People dancing.
      Trumpet player.
      Two people walking away from chapel.
      Girls doing can-can.
    - Duke vs. North Carolina, undated, 1 film reel: b&w; 7 inch. (Reel 30)
      about 300 ft.
      Old Duke Stadium.
      Band marching up field.
      Bill Murray talking with another coach.
      (21) kick on catch ball.
      (27) passing the ball.
      Football plays start.
      (17) quarterback takes the ball hands back to fullback left-handed pass down field.
      (47) running ball makes fine gain.
      (27) takes ball and scores.
      Shot of crowd.
      (17) passes ball to (8) who goes out of bounds.
      (17) bulldogs around side.
      Scoreboard Duke 13 Visitors 7.
      Touchdown and recovers fumble.
      Another touchdown.
      On 8 yard line.
      4th quarter 3 1/2 minutes to go score Duke 13, Visitors 21.
    - Duke Marine Laboratory, circa 1950, 1 film reel: b&w; 7 inch. (Reel 31)
      Aerial view of chapel.
      People walking in quad.
      Marine Laboratory bldg.
      Lab Dorms.
      Lab Workhouse.
      Inside of lab/people working.
      Beaufort in distance and old boats that were used.
      People back in lab.
    - Duke-Army Highlights, Comp. Sound, Print I, undated, 1 film reel: sd., b&w; 7 inch. (Reel 32)
      Panning down from quad toward athletic field.
      Teams playing on field.
      Scoreboard-apparently no score.
      Narrator-Ad Penfield, Edited by Tommy O'Boyle.
    - Duke-Army Football Highlights, Composite Sound Print #II, undated, 1 film reel: sd., b&w; 7 inch. (Reel 33)
      Same as reel 32.
    - Splendor from the Earth (Duke Gardens Film), undated, 1 film reel: sd., col.; 7 inch. (Reel 34)
      (Badly scratched)
    - Campus Scenes, Spring 1941, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel 35)
      In the Description of Films, Number 35 is entitled Life at Duke, 1941. The contents are listed as:
      Robert L. Flowers elected President of Duke.
      Executive Committee members met in front of Chapel.
      Alumnae-Alumni Weekend.
      Track, Baseball Duke defeats UNC 6-2 final game.
      May Day Fiesta-lots of color.
      Commencement.
      Academic procession.
      Introduction of Robert L. Flowers as President of Duke.
      Alumni Luncheon.
      Degrees conferred in University gym.
    - Duke Gardens, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 7 inch. (Reel 36)
      Titles of different plants we see.
      VERY BAD SPLICES.
    - Duke Gardens, circa 1937-1940, 1 film reel: col.; 7 inch. (Reel 37)
    - Year at Duke, circa 1941-1944, 1 film reel: col.; 7 inch. (Box 22, Reel 38)
      The dates 1941-42 and 1944 were both written on the original can in which this film was stored. The date 1944 is written on the reel. The typed Description of Films gives the date of reel 38 as 1941.
      Color Homecoming Display.
      Someone reading to group of students.
      Sign which reads: Notre Dame tried it, Auburn tried it, Navy tried it, Duke DOOD IT!
      Another sign,Welcome Brothers!
      Picnic or something.
      People sitting around eating something.
      Band and Navy squadron.
      American flag.
      Navy marches off field.
      Duke 58.3-Carolina Pre-flight 67.7.
      Track meet.
      Somebody out distancing the rest of crowd.
      Pole Vaulter.
      Several Pole Vaulters.
      Sign says Cornelius Warmerdam world champion pole vault clears the 13'6" mark.
      Here he comes.
      People running broad jump.
      Duke-Navy ROTC holds annual review.
      Marching on field.
      COLOR medals are presented for highest navigation and marksmanship.
      Alumni-Alumnae Luncheon.
      People eating.
      Commencement Scenes May 18th and 19th, 1942.
      Reception honoring graduating class and their parents.
      People in garden BLACK AND WHITE.
      Senior class lowers flag at sunset.
      1896 Reunion Dinner BLACK AND WHITE.
      Class of '41.
      Some members of classes of '32, '33, '34, '35.
      Group standing in front of chapel.
      Bishop Aden W. Leonard delivers commencement address at chapel.
      800 degrees conferred.
      Academic procession (very dark).
    - Orange Bowl Parade, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 5 inch. (Box 16, Reel 41)
      (very dark probably unusable).
      350-400 ft.
    - Duke Football, circa 1937-1941, 1 film reel: b&w; 7 inch. (Reel 42)
      Duke (86) taking a kick (11) & (20) around him.
      () passes down to (45) who catches and made a 5 yard gain.
      Ball goes out.
      (38) coming up field.
      One team wearing helmet with white X mark other team sort of a white dome on it.
      Both uniforms look identical.
      X team has ball (30) passing out to his right to (37) who runs out of bounds.
      Game took place in Duke outdoor stadium.
      (30) passing long down to (41) incompleted pass.
    - Year at Duke, 1937-1938, 1 film reel (400 ft.): b&w; 7 inch. (Reel 45)
      Duke University Women hold field day: Archery, Tennis, Softball, Horseback Riding, Steeple Chase.
      Carnation and Pageant -COLOR:
      Ceres & Prosperine is given for entertainment for Queen and her court.
      May Day Exercises long.
      Centennial Commencement.
      Representatives from 46 orphanages homes through the Carolinas aided by the Duke Endowment pace a wreath on the James B. Duke tomb in the Duke Memorial Chapel.
      Picture of wreath and two kids and a man.
      Candidates for degrees and their parents are honored at a reception.
      President Few and some other gentleman standing there.
      Some kind of reception out in the open.
      Academic procession marching into chapel.
      Alumni hold annual luncheon.
      Dr. Few and others receiving honorary degrees (left to right): Dr. W. P. Few, Dr. Norman Vincent Peale, Rev. J. B. Craven, Gov. Clyde R. Hoey, Dr. Lewis Hill Weed, Dr. Charles Holmes Herty.
      Procession going out into football stadium.
      Flag is lowered as final act of school year.
      Someone going up stands to get to the flag.
    - Splendor from the Earth, orig. Koda, undated., 1 film reel: col.; 7 inch. (Reel 46 pt. 1)
    - Splendor from the Earth, Track neg., Jan. 8, 1958, 1 film reel: 7 inch. (Reel 46 pt. 2)
    - Ace Parker 105 yd run & 70 yd return, undated, 1 film reel (47 secs.): si., b&w; 3 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Duke-Army Titles - Campus Views, undated, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Duke vs. Army Football Highlights Neg Track, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 7-inch can. (Reel No number)
    - Football Highlights, circa 1938, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Football: Purdue Rally Deadlocks Duke, undated, 1 film reel: sd., b&w; 3 inch. (Reel No number)
    - McAfee, undated, 1 film reel: col.; 3 inch. (Reel No number)
    - McAfee, undated, 1 film reel: b&w; 3 inch. (Reel No number)
    - G.E. College Bowl: Duke University, Apr. 15, 1960, 1 film reel: b&w; 7 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Old Athletics, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 7 inch can. (Reel No number)
    - Splendor from the Earth, undated, 1 film reel: sd., col.; 7 inch. (Reel No number)
    - Tipton, undated, 1 film reel: b&w; 5 inch. (Reel No number)
  - Film, Unnumbered 10 and 12 inch reels, circa 1948-1965, undated
    All of the film in this sub-series is 16mm on 10 or 12-inch reels. These reels seem to have been packed together simply because they were all about the same size.
    Some of the subjects depicted include Duke bands and the Marine Laboratory. There are original elements for the film Duke 140, as well as finished versions of the films Response to Our Challenge, Quest Without End, and This is Duke.
    Films are arranged alphabetically by title.
    Since these are not numbered using the Radio-TV Department's numbering system, and since most of them appear to have been shot before the creation of the department, it is assumed that they were inherited from some other organization.
    - Centennial Year, 1938-1939, 1 film reel (28 min., 1200 ft.): si., b&w; 10 inch. (Box 17)
      Reference Copy: VHS. UA88-57-14
      Reference Copy: DVD. UA88-57-14
      From an Initial Appraisal of this film, a copy of which is in Folder 13, Box 17:
      Events during the Fall Semester (about 10 minutes).
      Homecoming parade in Durham.
      Alumni Reunion and Barbecue.
      Residential quads with homecoming signs and displays.
      Duke-Georgia Tech football game.
      Boxing match.
      Duke-NCSU baseball game.
      Spring on the campus (lead-in to Centennial).
      The Centennial Weekend, Apr. 21-23, 1939 (about 15 minutes).
      Friday:
      Reception of delegates, H. M. Wriston speaks.
      Dedication of the Sarah P. Duke Gardens, band concert.
      Saturday a.m.: Education and the public.
      Trustees of Duke University and Duke Endowment.
      President Few introduces J. M. Finley (?).
      Speech by Edouard Benes.
      Saturday p.m.: The University and the Nation.
      Speakers.
      Dean Wannamaker introduces P. H. Hanes.
      P. F. Hanes hands packet to President Few to be opened in 100 years.
      Sunday a.m.:
      Chapel Service.
      Portrait of the celebrants.
      Audience for Carillon concert by Anton Brees.
      Year-end ceremonies (about 5 minutes).
      May Day Pageant, The Woman's College.
      The 87th Commencement:
      Representatives of orphanages preparing to lay wreath on JBD's tomb.
      Alumni registration and luncheon.
      Commencement ceremony.
      Family groups receiving degrees (twins, mother-daughter).
      Honorary degree recipients.
      Lowering of the flag.
    - Duke 140 Reel 1, undated, 1 film reel: 12 inch.
    - Duke 140 Reel 1 (of 2), undated, 1 film reel: 12 inch.
    - Duke 140 Reel 2, undated, 1 film reel: 12 inch.
    - Duke 140 A Roll, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
    - Duke 140 B Roll, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
    - Duke 140 Soundtrack Final transfer Part One, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
    - Duke 140 Soundtrack Final transfer Part Two, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
    - Duke Bands, 1948-1950, 1 film reel: 10 inch.
    - Duke Band, 1952, 1 film reel: 12 inch. (Box 18)
      Note on can: This film includes: